Alvina ONG, ONG Si Ying

Mobile: +65 9295 6807

Email: <a href="mailto:ongsiying@u.nus.edu">ongsiying@u.nus.edu</a>
Wechat: <a href="mailto:wxid\_8gay3p8427il22">wxid\_8gay3p8427il22</a>
Skype: <a href="mailto:live:alvina.ongg\_1">live:alvina.ongg\_1</a>

Github: https://www.github.com/siyingpoof

Online Resume: <u>www.ongsiying.com</u>



#### Personal Statement

# **Internship Objectives**

I believe strongly in the spirit of enterprising, empathy and innovation. Other than having the drive to start something I am truly passionate in, I must keep in mind the needs of my target audience, before developing something truly relevant for the community. Hence, with the opportunity to be part of the start-up scene in Silicon Valley, I wish to expose myself to the myriad of ideas and inspirations from the companies in a different culture than Singapore. On top of that, working in a start-up will enable me to discover the core functions of a start-up and ascertain my abilities and interests in certain areas.

### **About Me**

I am a sophomore in the Double Degree Program (DDP) under NUS, studying Business Administration (BBA) and Computer Science (CS). I am considering the Business Analytics or Finance specialization under BBA and the Software Engineering specialization under CS. The main reason I am in DDP is due to my interest in programming, which was sparked by a programming workshop I attended before my enrolment, and that it is an additional skillset I could acquire on top of the skills I will pick up in my BBA degree. My hobbies include leisure singing and photography. I enjoy nature and human photography the most, where I like to go out with my friends to take pictures during hikes or festivals.

# **Strengths and Weaknesses**

Empathy is my greatest strength is also one of my greatest weakness. I tend to put myself in other people's shoes too often and too deeply, which on the good side, allows me to obtain greater insights and think from their perspective how they would want this problem to be solved. However, on the bad side, I become too indecisive as I tend to overthink about all the possibilities. Over time, I have learnt to be more practical and be more focused. This forces me to take a step back and think thoroughly before making any decision.

# **Work Experience**

My most recent internship was with Vouch SG, which is a start-up company with strength of 6 based in Singapore and Indonesia that focuses on building quality chatbots for the Hotel and Food and Beverages industries. I was in charge of managing chatbots by observing its daily interactions with users and training the chatbot to keep up with the demands of the users. I also implemented a new feature, Room Status Check, which constitutes at least 80% of the chatbot's usage, and modified chatbot flows to enhance users' experience. I also assisted in a tender submission to create a nationwide chatbot for the tourism industry, and our team managed to clinch the tender which would potentially bring about millions of revenue for the company.

### **Unique Skill Sets**

I am a flexible individual, who can adapt to changes quickly to generate relevant ideas to the company and bring it to fruition. As in my previous internship, I had to understand the chatbot builder platform within a few days to begin building chatbots as soon as possible.

I am also well-equipped with common programming languages such as Java and Python, which allowed me to build a mobile application during my summer in 2018. Currently, I am learning HTML and CSS to prepare myself for possible front-end development for my future projects. For non-technical skill sets, I can articulate well and can organize information systematically, as done in my project reports.

### **How Can I Contribute**

I am open-minded to learn from more experienced individuals and eager to learn new skills required along the way. Given my skill sets and knowledge acquired from the technical and non-technical sides, I believe I am capable of ideating relevant solutions for the company and assist in the company in bringing the idea to fruition from the beginning to the end.

Alvina Ong Si Ying

# **Education**

Aug 2017 - Present	National University of Singapore Bachelor of Business Administration (Honours) and Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science (Course details in Appendix A)	Singapore
Jan 2015 - Dec 2016	<ul> <li>Victoria Junior College</li> <li>Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level</li> <li>Subjects: H2 Physics (B), H2 Chemistry (A), H2 Math (A), H2 Economics (A)</li> </ul>	Singapore
Work Experience		
Dec 2018 – Jan 2019	<ul> <li>Vouch SG (https://www.vouch.sg/) Intern</li> <li>Vouch SG: Singapore tech start-up in the chatbot industry currently focused on digital concierges for the hotel industries.</li> <li>Analysed users' interactions with the chatbots in the hotel and food and beverages industries and trained the chatbots to enhance user experience.</li> <li>Wrote functional requirements on the proposed nationwide chatbot for tourists' usage which Vouch clinched the tender.</li> <li>Formulated weekly reports to review users' satisfaction and enhanced user's experience by introducing a new feature (Room Status Check) that accounts for 80% of the chatbot's main usage, also resulting in reduced manhours of the front desk.</li> </ul>	Singapore
Apr 2017 - Jun 2017	<ul> <li>Hugo Boss Retail Assistant <ul> <li>Proactive in assisting the full-time staff in the maintenance of the storefront and customer service and sales.</li> <li>Tasked to maintain neatness of the stocks in the storeroom.</li> </ul> </li> </ul>	Singapore
Feb 2017 – Mar 2017  Scholastic Achiever	<ul> <li>Cruger Haus (<a href="http://crugerhaus.sg/">http://crugerhaus.sg/</a>)</li> <li>Research Assistant</li> <li>Analysed and extracted relevant data from market surveys on hundreds of participants on smoking in Singapore and plotted current trends of the participants' demographics with respect to smoking habits for the client.</li> <li>Conducted follow-up validation on 100 survey respondents to ensure quality of surveys done.</li> </ul>	Singapore
Aug 2017 - Present	Scholarship NUS Business Dean's Scholarship (academic excellence)  • Awarded to 5% of AY17/18 NUS School of Business cohort	Singapore
May 2018 - Sep 2018	<ul> <li>NUS School of Computing (SoC) Orbital</li> <li>Orbital (<a href="https://orbital.comp.nus.edu.sg/">https://orbital.comp.nus.edu.sg/</a>): SoC's freshmen summer self-directed, independent work course.</li> <li>Developed a mobile application prototype which facilitates the recruitment of volunteers for non-governmental organization (NGO) projects.</li> <li>Integrated Firebase and our application to extract and display the correct</li> </ul>	Singapore

Alvina Ong Si Ying 2

Integrated Firebase and our application to extract and display the correct data on the Android Studio platform.

### Oct 2018 – Mar 2019 Community Service (Project Spright Academy)

- Singapore
- Project Spright Academy: A NUS Scholars' Program for scholars to give back to the society by engaging under-privileged children.
- Planned meaningful activities of different elements (environmental awareness, baking, language appreciation, physical activities and music appreciation) for children from low-income families.
- Engaged the children over the course of 5 consecutive weekdays and
  positive feedback on the activities prepared were given by the staff and the
  students.

# Aug 2017 - Present School Contributions (University)

Singapore

- Vice President of Student Development, NUS Students' Computing Club
  - NUS Students' Computing Club (<a href="https://nuscomputing.com/">https://nuscomputing.com/</a>): A faculty club that comprises and represents all undergraduates pursuing a degree in NUS School of Computing.
- Internal Marketing Head, NUS Business School Alumni Youth Wing
  - NUS Business School Alumni Youth Wing (<a href="https://www.bsayouthwing.com/">https://www.bsayouthwing.com/</a>): Serves as the outreach arm for students and young alumni of NUS Business School.
- Publicity member, Business School Freshmen Orientation Week 2018
- Manpower member, School of Computing Freshmen Social Camp 2018

Jan 2016 - July 2016 Victoria

### Victoria Junior College

Singapore

• Member of Photography Society

# **Skill Sets & Proficiency**

Multimedia	Adobe Photoshop	Basic
Web	HTML, CSS	Intermediate
Database	Firebase	Proficient
Programming	Java C Python	Proficient Intermediate Intermediate
Scripting	JavaScript	Basic
Markup	XML	Basic
<b>Operating Systems</b>	Linux Windows 10, 8	Basic Basic
Office Productivity	Microsoft Word, PowerPoint Microsoft Excel	Proficient Intermediate

# Language Proficiency

SpokenEnglish – fluent; Mandarin – fluentWrittenEnglish – competent; Chinese – competent

### **Additional Information**

Other activities/interests Music, Photography (Nature, Human)

Alvina Ong Si Ying 3

**Degree:** Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science and Bachelor of Business Administration (Honours) **Cumulative Average Point: 4.00** / **5.00** 

Category	Year/Level	Course Description	Grades
Computer Science Foundation	Year 1/Semester 1	Programming Methodology	S
	Year 2/Semester 1	Programming Methodology II	A-
	Year 1/Semester 2	Data Structures and Algorithm	B-
	Year 1/Semester 2	Discrete Structures	B+
	Year 2/Semester 2	Linear Algebra	Ongoing
	Year 2/Semester 2	Calculus for Computing	Ongoing
	Year 2/Semester 1	Computer Organization	B+
Software Engineering	Year 1/Summer	Independent Software Development Project (Orbital)	CS
	Year 2/Semester 2	Software Engineering	Ongoing
IT Professionalism	Year 1/Semester 2	Business Communications for Leaders (BBA)	B+
Business Core Modules	Year 2/Semester 2	Programming for Business Analytics	Ongoing
	Year 1/Semester 2	Decision Analytics using Spreadsheets	B+
	Year 2/Semester 1	Finance	B+
	Year 2/Semester 1	Operations and Technology Management	A-
	Year 1/Semester 1	Principles of Marketing	B+
	Year 1/Semester 1	Managerial Economics	B+
	Year 2/Semester 2	Global Economy	Ongoing
	Year 1/Semester 1	Legal Environment of Business	S
	Year 1/Semester 1	Accounting for Decision Makers	S

# The **Software Engineering Project** focuses on designing and implementing a tool called a Static Program Analyzer (SPA). A SPA reads in a program written in SIMPLE and answers user's queries based on the input program. This allows the user to gain an understanding of the input program, which is especially useful when the input program is long and complex. This is a project done in a team of 6 people. This team is further sub-divided into 2 teams with 3 members each. The 2 teams would tackle 2 different areas, namely the Program Knowledge Base (PKB) and the Program Query Language (PQL). The PKB handles the parsing and storing of the input program into its data structures. Whereas, the PQL receive queries from the user and builds a query tree. The nodes from the query tree then query the PKB through a façade to retrieve the corresponding datasets in a leaf to root node traversal, performing cross-products or intersections along the way. The final result is then displayed to the user via a result projector using a Graphical User Interface (GUI).

### **NUS Grading Scale:**

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn

Alvina Ong Si Ying 4

#### **VOUCH SG PTE LTD**

71 Ayer Rajah Crescent #01-21, Singapore 139951 www.vouch.sg

Date: 24 January 2019

Joseph Ling Chief Executive Officer 71 Ayer Rajah Crescent #01-21 Singapore 139951

# **Letter of Recommendation for Ong Si Ying**

To Whom It May Concern,

I would like to recommend Ong Si Ying for the NOC programme. Si Ying was an intern with Vouch during her winter break from December 2018 to January 2019, where she displayed great initiative and entrepreneurial qualities.

Si Ying was not afraid to take on the challenges given to her, and she takes ownership of projects to ensure smooth execution. She was put in-charge of building and launching our ParkRoyal Kitchener (PRK) digital concierge, Kit. Not only did she build a bot that had few bugs (no mean feat), she constantly managed the different stakeholders expertly to ensure that the bot was launched on time and smoothly.

After its launch, when we experienced many teething issues, Si Ying demonstrated grit, nimbleness of mind and creativity to iterate and improve core parts of the bot quickly. Despite initial setbacks, Si Ying constantly took it upon herself to ideate new ways to increase the chatbot's usage by increasing visibility of Kit and managed to persuade PRK's staff to actively promote it.

During her internship, Si Ying expressed interest in one day being an entrepreneur. From the qualities that I have observed in her short one month stint with us, I think she has what it takes and should be given an opportunity to learn more about startups. She is also receptive and respectful towards ideas and criticism given by other employees and interns, and would make a fine founder/startup employee one day.

Hence, I would like to recommend Si Ying for the NOC programme as she would be able to contribute to any startup with her strength of mind, dedication, and willingness to learn.

Thank you.

Best Regards,

Joseph Ling